Finding aid for Library (University of Michigan) Clipping file, ca. 1920-1980
Bentley Historical Library
- University of Michigan
  - C
    - Civilian Defense. (Box 7)
      (see also: Hospitals (for disaster program); Ann Arbor-Defense (general file); various RTC, NROTC, etc. folders)
    - Civilian Pilot Training Program.
      (see: Aviation)
    - Class Ranking (of male students for draft board reports, 1966-see: Student Records
    - Classical Courier. Dept newspaper.
    - Classical Studies, Dept. of 1946- (Box 7)
      (Includes Classical Archaeology, Classical Linguistics, Greek Lang. and Literature, Latin Lang. and Lit.)
    - Classification.
      (see: Registration and Classification)
    - Classroom Scheduling Service.
      (see: University Relations Service)
    - Claude Commission Report on Students' Role.
      (see: Student, Faculty, Administration Relations)
    - Clements (William Lawrence) Library
      (see also: Faculty-Adams, Randolph; Faculty-Peckham, Howard)
      - 1926-1933 (Box 7)
      - 1934-1937 (Box 7)
      - 1938-1945 (Box 7)
      - 1945-1951 (Box 7)
    - "Clippy's Stadium".
    - Clocks.
      (see: Buildings and Grounds; Burton Tower)
    - (Charles)Coffin Fellowships.
      (see: Fellowships)
    - Coif, Order of.
      (see: Societies-Coif, Order of)
    - Coins.
      (see: Museums (in Museum of Anthropology))
    - College Administration, Conferences (Institutes) on
      (see: Summer Session-Institutes)
    - College and University Teaching.
      (see: Education, School of-Higher education)
    - Colleges, Residential.
      (see: Literary College-Residential College; Education, School of (for Education Residential Program))
    - Collegium Musicum. (Box 7)
      (Includes other ensembles devoted to Ren., Med., and baroque music. Sponsors the Tudor Singers (vocal group). see also: Chamber Music)
    - Comedy Club.
      (see: Dramatics-Comedy Club)
    - Commencement.
      (see also: Seniors)
      - 1920-1924 (Box 8)
      - 1925-1929 (Box 8)
      - 1930-1934 (Box 8)
      - 1935-1945 (Box 8)
      - 1946-1950 (Box 8)
      - 1951-1960 (Box 8)
      - 1961-1976 (Box 8)
    - Commencement Band.
      (see: Bands-Symphony Band)
    - Commission on Human Resources and Advanced Training-a senior vocational survey, 1953.
      (see: Seniors)
    - Commission on the Role of Students in Decision-Making.
    - Committee for displaced students.
      (see: Foreign Students-Displaced persons)
    - Committee for Liberal Action.
      (see: Political Clubs-Committee for Liberal Action)
    - Committee on Classified Research.
      (see: Research.)
    - Committee on College Relations
      (see: Education, School of-Higher Education Committee on Discrimination in Off-Campus Housing, see: Race Relations Committee on Institutional Cooperation (CIC). see: Joint Programs (General))
    - (University) Committee on Studies in Religion. Sponsors lectures on religious topics.
    - Committee to End Discrimination
    - Common Sense Party.
      (see: Student Government (19514-5))
    - Communication Sciences (Box 8)
    - Communications Media, Committee on.
      (see: Publications)
    - Communism.
      (see: Political Clubs-Communist; Radicals; Free Speech)
    - Community Relations. (Box 8)
      (Includes material on "fair share" of costs of city services, city fire and police protection, "town and gown" problems that do not fit under more specific subjects. see also: Student, Faculty, Administration Relations; Housing)
    - Community Service Committee.
      (see: Women's League-Activities Community Sings. see: Glee Clubs-Misc.)
    - Comparative Education, Program in.
      (see: Education, School of-Workshops)
    - Composer's Forums.
      (see: Music, School of)
    - Comprehensive Examinations
      (see: Literary College Computers)
    - Computers (Box 8)
    - Concentration Advisors
      (see: Advisors)
    - Concerned Clerics for Action. See CCA/UAW
    - Conference on Aging.
      (see: Institute for Hunan Adjustment-Gerontology, Div. of)
    - Conference on Environmental Mercury Contamination. See Institute of Industrial Health
    - Conference on Higher Education.
      (see: Universities and Colleges-Michigan; Education, School of-; Higher Education)
    - Conference on Hospital Management.
    - Conference on Organ Music. See Organ
    - Conference on Student Exchanges, 19118.
      (see: Foreign Students)
    - Conference on the Economic Outlook.
      (see: Economics, Dept. of-Conference on the Economic Outlook)
    - Conference on the University (May 1962-)
      (see: Administration)
    - Conference on World Understanding, 1947.
      (see: Extension-Institutes)
    - Conference Research. Sponsored by the Office of Naval Research and carried on by the Psychology Dept., U of N.
      (see: Psychology, Dept. of)
    - Conferences.
      (see: Campus Events; Summer Session-Institutes; Summer Session-Campus-Events; Extension-Press Releases (filed by date held); various groups holding the conference)
    - Conflict Resolution.
    - Congress. (Box 8)
      (Official title of the,Independent Men's Association. 1937-44. Superseded by Association for Independent Men.)
    - Conscientious Objectors.
      (see: Religion (for students); Faculty-Morgan; Conscientious Objectors (general file); Military Affairs, Office of)
    - Conscription see: Military Affairs, Office of Conservation, Dept. of. 2.22: Natural Resources, School of
    - Consortium for Political Research (Inter-University).
      (see: Institute for Social Research-Survey Research Center)
    - Consumer Finance Surveys.
    - Consumer's Union.
      (see: Expenses, Student)
    - Contemporary.
      (see: Student Publications-Literary)
    - Contemporary Directions.
    - Contemporary Literature Club.
    - Contemporary Music Festival.
      (see: Music, School of-Extension Program)
    - Continuing Education of Women, Center for.
      (see: Center for continuing Education of Women)
    - Continuing Engineering Education, Chrysler Center for.
    - Contributions of the Negro (Patterns of American Culture I)
      (see: Summer Session-Campus Events (1956))
    - "Controversy "68" Programs.
    - Convocations.
      (see also: Honors Convocations; Student Christian Association (for non-university sponsored programs))
      - 1920-September 1929 (Box 8)
      - October 1929 (Box 8)
      - 1964 (Box 8)
    - John P. Cook Dormitory.
      (see: Law School-Law Quadrangle)
    - W. W. Cook Endowment for Legal Research.
      (see: Law School-W.W. Cook Foundation; Law School-Legal Research)
    - Cooley Memorial Lab.
      (For building see: North Campus research; see North Campus-Research by Non-University Firms.; Engineering, College of---North Campus-and departments doing research.)
    - Cooperative Council.
    - Co-op Houses.
      (see: Cooperative rooming and boarding projects)
    - Cooperative Information Center on Hospital Management Studies.
      (see: Bureau of Hospital Administration)
    - Cooperative Movement.
      (see: Extension-Southeastern Area (courses offered in))
    - Cooperative Rooming and Boarding Projects.
      (Includes those of the Inter-cooperative Council (see that card for list) and the following-Alumnae Council operates (operated); Alumnae Hall, 1917-became (Mary) Markley House (women)-closed 1950. (Mary Bartron) Henderson House (women); Comm. for International Living operates (ed) (J. Raleigh) Nelson international House 1950-(men) (Adelia) Cheever House; Wolverine Cooperative Exchange (student coop eating club) 1930-became the Michigan Wolverine Restaurant.)
      - 1932-1938 (Box 8)
      - 1939-1945 (Box 8)
      - 1946-1952 (Box 8)
      - 1953 (Box 8)
    - Cooperative Stores.
      (Includes textbook exchanges.)
      - 1920-1945 (Box 8)
      - 1946- (Box 8)
    - Core Library.
      (see: Geology, Dept. of)
    - Correspondence Courses.
      (see: Extension-Correspondence Study Courses. Bulletins in North Campus and U of M Collection.)
    - Cosmopolitan Club.
      (see: Foreign Students-Societies-Cosmopolitan Club)
    - Council. Created as a smaller governing unit of the Faculty Senate, 1931-
      (see: Senate (Faculty))
    - Council for International Living
      (Sponsors international houses for the foreign students. see Foreign Students-Housing)
    - (National) Council of Arts, Sciences and Professions (Michigan Chapter).
    - Council on International Student Exchange (faculty group) 'see: Foreign Students
    - Counseling System.
      (see: Advisors, Freshmen; Student Affairs, Office of; Health Service (for Mental Health Clinic))
    - Course Critique program.
      (see: Advisors Course evaluations. see: Faculty Evaluations Cowie Lectures. see: Medical School)
    - Crease Ball.
    - Creative Arts Festival.
      (see: Union-Activities (Through 1964); University Activities Center (1965-))
    - Credit Unions.
      (see: Employees (Michigan Employee Credit Union); Hospitals (Hospital Credit Union))
    - Crest Club.
      (see: Employees)
    - Crime.
      (see also: Public Health, School of; Student Govt. (Joint Judiciary Council); Marking System (for exam thefts))
      - 1925-1954 (Box 8)
      - 1955-12964 (Box 8)
      - 1965-1968 (Box 8)
      - 1968-1972 (Box 8)
      - 1972- (Box 8)
    - Crop and Saddle (Women's riding club).
    - Cube, Kinetic, on Jefferson Plaza.
      (see: Memorials (This is not a memorial, however))
    - Cudlip (Robert S.) Fellowship.
    - Culture Club.
      (see: Societies-Culture Club)
    - Arthur G. Cummer Firearms Collection.
      (see: Kelsey Museum of)
    - Archaeology
    - Curriculum.
      (Includes language requirements. For requirements of a particular dept., see that dept. see also: Honors Program)
      - 1925-1939 (Box 8)
      - 1940-1953 (Box 8)
      - 1954- (Box 8)
    - Cyclotron.
      (see: Physics, Dept. of)
  - D
    - Daily.
      (see: Michigan Daily)
    - Dance. (Box 9)
      (for dance clubs, performances, classes, activities. see also: Music Series (includes: Chamber Dance Festival, Dance Series); Dramatics-Professional Theater Program (for dance performances sponsored by the Profession al Theater Program); Foreign Students-International Center; Foreign Students-International Students Association; Summer Session-Campus Events (1957))
    - Dance Festival.
    - Dance Series.
    - Date Bureau.
      (see: Student Life)
    - Dating Lab.
    - Day Care Center. (Box 9)
      (note: includes day care controversy)
    - Deaf.
    - Dean (Stanley R,.) Award
      (see: Mental Health Research Institute)
    - Dean -- Men, 1920-1962
      (see: Student Affairs, Office of; see also: Student Affairs Committee (1921-55); Student Government-Board of Review; Advisors)
      - 1920-1950 (Box 9)
      - 1951-1961 (Box 9)
    - Dean-Women, 1920-1962 (Box 9)
      (see: Student Affairs, Office of; see also: Student Affairs Committee (1921-55); Student Government-Board of Review)
    - Dearborn Center (i.e. Dearborn Campus)
      - Thru, 1962
      - 1963
    - Debating and Oratory-
      (see also: Societies-Debating and Oratory; Societies-Sigma Rho Tau; Forums (card); Extension-Debating; Union Activities; Foreign Students-International Student Association; Foreign Students-International Center; Parlays)
      - 1920-1925 (Box 9)
      - 1926-1928 (Box 9)
      - 1929-1935 (Box 9)
      - 1935-1947 (Box 9)
      - 1948- (Box 9)
    - Debating and Oratory-Women (Box 9)
    - Degrees (awarded).
      (see: Commencement)
    - Delta College, Proposed Affiliation. (Box 9)
    - Delta Epsilon Pi. A society of the Eastern Orthodox Church.
      (see: Religion-Churches.)
    - Delta Omicron. Professional Music Society. (Box 9)
    - Delta Phi Alpha. National Honorary German Fraternity, 1929.
      (see: Societies-Foreign Language)
    - Delta Pi Epsilon (National Honorary Fret. of Bus. Education).
    - Delta Sigma Delta. Dental Fraternity.
      (see: Dentistry, School of)
    - Delta Sigma Pi. (Prof. Bus. Ad. Fret.).
    - Delta Sigma Rho.
    - Democrats. Student activities.
      (see: Political Clubs-Democrats; Faculty and general see Elections-National, State, and Local; names of individuals, e.g. Faculty-Eldersveld, Samuel.)
    - Dental Hygienists.
    - Dentistry, School of
      (For additional information see also: Alumni Bulletin at the Dentistry Library)
      - 1923-1952 (Box 9)
      - 1954-1966 (Box 9)
      - 1967 (Box 9)
    - Dentistry, School of-Societies.
      (see: Societies-Dentistry.)
    - Detroit Area Study.
      (see: Institute for Social Research-Detroit Area Study.)
    - Detroit Public School Computer Project.
      (see: Joint Programs-(General))
    - Detroit Public School System.
    - Deutscher Verein.
      (see: Societies-Deutscher Verein)
    - Deutsches Haus (German Lang. House).
      (see: Germanic Languages and Literatures, Dept. of)
    - Development Council.
    - Development of Academic Opportunities, University Steering Committee on.
    - Dietetics.
    - Dimension.
      (see: Architecture and Design, College of)
    - Diploma and Diploma Office.
    - Directory.
    - Disappearance of Students.
      (see: Student Life-Individuals;)
    - Foreign Students
    - Disciples of Christ.
      (see: Religion-Churches-Congregational)
    - Discipline.
      (see: Student Affairs Committee; Joint Judiciary; Administration; Dean (Men); Dean (Women); Fraternities-Discipline; Prohibition; Judiciaries (card lists how handled in dorms); Student Life; Student Life-Individuals; Crime; Radicals)
    - Discipline Committee., 1926-1939
      (see: Student Affairs Committee.)
    - Discrimination.
      (see: Race Relations.)
    - Disease.
      (see: Health Service (For other people involved see also: Foreign Students; Faculty; Employees, etc.))
    - Displaced Persons.
      (see: Foreign Students-Displaced Persons)
    - Dissent Forum.
      (see: Forums)
    - .Distinguished University Professorships.
      (see: Faculty (General); Faculty, A-Z;)
    - Division of Research Development and Administration. see also Office of Research Administration (Box 9)
    - DoDos. Artist and dramatic group of faculty, students and towns people formed 19181 Became Ann Arbor Playmakers 1924.
      (see: Dramatics-Faculty and town groups)
    - Dormitories- (Box 9)
      (General (Includes Co-ed Dorms, 1962-) see also: Dormitories-Men; Dormitories-women; Housing;)
    - Dormitories-Inter-House Assembly. (Box 9)
      (Formed in 1966 by merger of Assembly Association and Interquadrangle Council. see also: Dormitories-Men-Inter-House Council (before 1966); Assembly)
    - Dormitories-Men.
      (see also: Dormitories-Men-Inter-house Council; Societies-Quadrants; Food Service Bldg; Housing; For Co-ed Dorms (1962-) see Dormitories-General)
      - 1923-1935 (Box 9)
      - 1936-1938 (Box 9)
      - 1939-1946 (Box 9)
      - 1947-1949 (Box 9)
      - 1950-1951 (Box 9)
      - 1952-1953 (Box 9)
      - 1954- (Box 9)
    - Dormitories-Men-Inter-House Council, 1952-1966
      (In 1966 merged with Assembly to form Inter-House Assembly)
      - 1952-June 1957 (Box 9)
      - July 1957-January 1958 (Box 9)
    - Dormitories-Women.
      (see also: Food Service Building; Housing; Housing-Women. For co-ed dorms (1962-) see Dormitories-general.)
      - 1920-1928 (Box 10)
      - 1929-1931 (Box 10)
      - 1931-1943 (Box 10)
      - 1943-1949 (Box 10)
      - 1950-1953 (Box 10)
      - 1954- (Box 10)
    - Double Ten Day. Chinese holiday.
    - Draft, Military.
      (see: Military Affairs, Office of; Student Records (for class ranking of males subject to draft, 1966-)
    - Draft Counseling Center (1968-in First Baptist Church).
      (see: Military Affairs, Office of)
    - Drama Season Board 1957-
      (see: Dramatics-Dramatic Festival)
    - Dramatic Festival.
    - Dramatic Season.
    - Dramatics.
      (Includes one act plays; Speech Dept. readers' theater and experimental playbills: misc. short plays; general data; visiting groups not in the Dramatic Festival series; and the following misc. groups-Committee on Dramatics, U of M Players, Harris Players, Laboratory Playbill, Teachers Dramatic Workshop. For other misc. groups, see Dramatics-Student groups (include Residential College Players); Dramatics-Student Players; Dramatics-Faculty and town groups; see also: Power Center for the Performing Arts; Play Production (3 Acts); Dramatics-Rockford Players (1924-32); Dramatics-Dramatic Festival (1933-); Dramatics-Repertory Players (1933-); Dramatics-Professional Theater Program.)
      - 1920-1937 (Box 10)
      - 1937-1948 (Box 10)
      - 1948-1950 (Box 10)
      - 1951-1955 (Box 10)
      - 1956-1965 (Box 10)
      - 1965-1968 (Box 10)
      - 1968-1971 (Box 10)
      - 1972-1974 (Box 10)
    - Dramatics (Plays by special groups)
      (see: Dramatics-Children's Theater Dramatics-Comedy Club Dramatics-Masques; Eng. Lang. and Lit, Dept. (play publication); Junior Girls' Play; League-Lydia Mendelssohn Theater; Opera; Play Production (3 Acts); Senior Girls' Play; Union-Opera; Union-Opera --Mimes; Societies-Hillel; Union-Theater; Ann Arbor-Theater)
    - Dramatics-Children's Theater 1933-) Supported by U of M Dept. of Speech in later years. (Box 10)
    - Dramatics-Comedy Club,., 1885-1935 (Box 10)
    - Dramatics-Dramatic Festival (1933-)
      (see: Dramatics-Rockford Players (1924-32) For earlier material)
      - 1930-1932 (Box 10)
      - 1933-1935 (Box 10)
      - 1936-1939 (Box 10)
      - 1944-1949 (Box 10)
      - 1950-1952 (Box 10)
      - 1953-1955 (Box 10)
      - 1956 (Box 10)
    - Dramatics-Faculty and town groups (Box 10)
      (Includes Dodos (1918-) who changed in 1924 to Ann Arbor Playmakers; Hampstead Community Players (1936-7); Nell Gwyn Company (1930-8?))
    - Dramatics-Masques. Women's dramatic society 1915-28. (Box 10)
    - Dramatics-Professional Theater Program---Clippings and-Pamphlets (Box 10)
    - Dramatics-Repertory Players (1933-), 2 folders
      (Summer session playbills of the Dept. of Speech at the Lydia Mendelssohn Theater. For earlier material see Dramatics-Rockford Players (1924-32). For outside groups see Dramatics-Dramatic Festival and Dramatics. see also: Faculty-Windt)
      - 1929-1935 (Box 11)
      - 1936-1941 (Box 11)
      - 1942-1947 (Box 11)
      - 1948-1951 (Box 11)
      - 1951- (Box 11)
    - Dramatics-Rockford Players, etc. (1924-32). For later activity (Box 11)
      (see: Dramatics-Dramatic Festival (1933-); Dramatics-Repertory Players (1933-).)
    - Dramatics-Student Groups (misc.) (Box 11)
      (Includes: The Players (1926); Players Club (192Q-5); Mummers (Women's Society) (1926-31); University Terrace Players; Packard Avenue Playreaders (P.A.P.) Medieval Festival; The Overland Stage)
    - Dramatics-Student Players. (Box 11)
      (Called Little Theater of Willow Village 1946-. Moved to Ann Arbor and became U. of M. Student Players 1948-. Theater Guild, an independent group set up in 1949 joined Student Players in 1958.)
    - Drinking ban.
      (see: Prohibition)
    - Driver Training Program.
    - Driving Ban.
      (see: Students, Autos)
    - Dropouts.
      (see: Enrollments.)
    - Drug Information Center.
      (see: Hospitals. Located in University Hospital Pharmacy.)
    - Drug Teach-In.
      (see: University Activities Center (Sponsored by UAC (Student Govt. Council et al, January 7, 1968-.))
    - Drugs research.
    - Drugs, University Committee on.
      (see: Michigan. University. Student Life)
    - Druids.
      (see: Societies-Druids)
    - Drum Major Contests.
    - Dubois (W.E.B.) Club.
      (see: Political Clubs (Gen.))
    - Duo Concertante. See Chamber Music
    - Dutch Settlement Celebration, 1947.
      (see: Campus Events 1947-9.)
  - E
    - ENACT (Environmental Action for Survival)
    - Economic behavior program.
      (see: Institute for Social Research-)
    - Survey Research Center
    - Economic Education, Michigan Council on.
    - Economic Outlook, Conference on.
      (see: Economics, Dept., of-Conference on the Economic-Outlook)
    - Economic Reconstruction of Europe.
      (see: Summer Session-Campus Events (19) 8)
    - Economics Club.
      (see: Economics, Dept. of)
    - Economics, Dept. (Box 11)
      (of see also: Economics, Dept. of-Conference on the Economic outlook; Woytinsky (W.S.) Lectureship Award;)
    - Economics, Dept. of-Conference on the Economic Outlook
    - Ecumenical Campus Center.
    - Education, School of.
      (Includes general information, Honors Convocation, conferences held. see also: Education, School of-Workshops; Education, School of-Summer Educ. Conf.; Bureau of School Services; Graduate School (H.H. Rackham)-State Teachers Colleges; Education, School of-Elementary School; Education, School of-Univ. High School; Education, School of-Laboratory School;)
      - 1920-1927 (Box 11)
      - 1928-1930 (Box 11)
      - 1931-1933 (Box 11)
      - 1934-1937 (Box 11)
      - 1937-1941 (Box 11)
      - 1943-1947 (Box 11)
      - 1948-1951 (Box 11)
      - 1952-1954 (Box 11)
      - 1955-1971 (Box 11)
      - 1972- (Box 11)
    - Education, School of-Elementary School of (Box 11)
      (After 1955-see Education; School of-Laboratory School)
    - Education, School of-Higher Education. (Box 11)
      (Includes Center for the Study of Higher Educ.; Conference on Higher Educ.; Seminar on Univ. Admin.;)
    - Education, School of-Laboratory School (Box 11)
      (Elementary and Secondary combined into one laboratory school 1955-. Previous years see Education, School of-Elementary; Education, School of Univ. High School.)
    - Education, School of-Summer Education Conference 1929-
      - 1929-1956 (Box 11)
      - 1957- (Box 11)
    - Education, School of-University High School. After, 1955 (Box 12)
      (see: Education, School of-Laboratory School)
    - Education, School of-Workshops.
      (For field courses see regular announcements by the School of Education. see also: Education, School of-Summer Education Conferences)
      - 1939-1952 (Box 12)
      - 1953- (Box 12)
    - Education-Russia.
      (see: Foreign Students-Societies-Europe (Symposium on Soviet Education on held by Ukrainian Student Club,1958) Slavic Languages and Literatures, Dept.; Education-Russian (general file))
    - Education Club.
      (see: Societies-Education)
    - Educational Communications System (ECS).
    - Educational Television and Radio Center, Ann Arbor (non-university).
      (see: Television-Educational Applications (general file))
    - Elderfield Report on Classified Research.
      (see: Research)
    - Elections.
      (see also: Student Government)
      - 1920-1929 (Box 12)
      - 1930-1937 (Box 12)
      - 1938-1946 (Box 12)
      - 1947-1949 (Box 12)
      - 1950-1953 (Box 12)
      - 1954-1956 (Box 12)
      - 1957 (Box 12)
    - Elections-National, State, and Local. (Box 12)
      (Includes views of candidates on University questions; views of faculty and students on election questions; faculty participation in elections, students registering to vote in Ann Arbor. For election of the Board of Regents see also: Regents see also: names of individuals Faculty-Eldersveld, Samuel; Faculty-Slosson, Preston; .Institute of Social Research-Survey Research Center (for surveys done))
    - Electro-Optical Sciences Laboratory.
      (see: Institute of Science and Technology.)
    - Elementary School.
      (see: Education, School of-Laboratory School (1955-).Education, School of-Elementary School)
    - Eligibility, Athletic.
    - Emergency Fund for Foreign Students.
      (Money raised by International Students Association see also: Foreign Students-International Center)
    - Employees.